

Amarachi Ajah

Software Engineer

Solution-driven web developer who is adept at contributing to a highly collaborative work environment and finding solutions. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using Angular, React, and Nextjs. Good knowledge of the best practices for web design, user experience, and speed.

Mobile: +234 806 518 8884 Portfolio: Portfolio Website

LinkedIn:amarachi-ajahBehance:BehanceEmail:anitamarachi@yahoo.comGitHub:AnitaAO

Work Experience

Employer: Prunedge Technologies

Address: 32 Ade Ajayi St, Ogudu GRA 100242, Lagos.

Position: Associate Software Engineer

Date: July 2022 - Till Date

Job Description

- Modified HTML, CSS, Javascript, and Typescript to optimize the page's performance for faster loading and browsing
- Utilized strategic engineering procedures to maintain and improve the company's point of sales system features that were built through Angular, React, Redux, JQuery, DotNet, Python, and C-Sharp languages.
- Designed and executed a brand-new retail management solution 'Boosta' along with a team to help small and medium enterprises scale.

Employer: Phareztech

Address: 4, Ogunbadejo street, Bariga, Lagos, Nigeria

Position: Software Developer **Date:** January 2021 - June 2022

Job Description

- Provided prompt solutions and proactive troubleshooting support that swiftly resolve subtle issues as a junior developer to the software engineering team.
- Determined areas of improvement by consistently reviewing bugs/fixes/codes
- Work with UI/UX team to handle new projects

Employer: Lepsta

Address: 1 Bellingham St, Highveld, Centurion, 0157, South Africa

Position: Regional Manager East & West Africa

Date: June 2018 - December 2019

Job Description

- Find sponsors for EngineOne activities in West & Eastern Africa.
- Identify opportunities to expand the community through partnerships and entering new cities
- Analyze the market to gain insights into how to improve performance and maximize the growth of the community
- Represent the region (West & Eastern Africa) in tech events
- Define the community target state, work plan, and work streams focusing on impact together with the global champion and team.
- Support local groups in implementation, track progress and communicate with the global admin team (Guidione and Kabelo)
- Identify performance gaps and initiate and roll out improvement projects.

Employer: Lepsta

Address: 1 Bellingham St, Highveld, Centurion, 0157, South Africa

Position: Local Leader **Date:** Feb 2018 - June 2018

Job Description

- Establish the EngineOne Community in Lagos, Nigeria.
- Expand the community to other major cities across Nigeria
- Engage and grow the community from 1 to 200 community members
- Organize local tech events in Lagos.
- Represent the community in the maiden edition of the Angel-Hackathon competition in Lagos.
- Write monthly reports to Guidione and Kabelo (Community Managers).
- Identify performance gaps and initiate and roll out improvement projects.

Employer: <u>Techville Nigeria</u>

Address: 48, Lagos Road, Ikorodu, Lagos.

Position: Web Designer & User Experience Engineer

Date: October 2017 - October 2019

Job Description

- Create Figma files for visual layout of iOS, Android, and web pages
- Graphics design, UI, and UX development into customer specifications
- Come up with simple logo designs where necessary
- Implement and maintain high-quality SEO policies and incorporate them with content produced for the website
- Implement and maintain high-quality SEO policies and incorporate them with content produced for the website
- Work with UX developers in creating mock-ups for proposed project pages and update them as needed.
- Interpret and convert UI designs into websites using WordPress CMS, HTML, and JavaScript.

Proficiencies

AngularCLI, React, NextJS, UI Development, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, WordPress, Figma, Illustrator, Material UI, Tailwind.

Angular Proficiencies

Modular Angular Architecture, Attribute and Structural Directives, Forms, and Validation (Template and Reactive Forms), Feature Modules and Routing, Route Guards, Custom Pipes, Binding, and Dependency Injection.

Strengths

- AGILE Development workflow
- Ability to disseminate information and communicate (explain) code language effectively
- Ability to break long-term goals into short term easily achievable lines codes
- Ability to sustain composure and maintain optimum output level within the project timesheet.
- Ability to work with a team, delegate, schedule activities, predict and envisage the needs of clients and ask for help as soon as needed
- Maximum exposure to diverse ethnic cultures, official work environment, and design.

Education

*	Lagos State University, Ojo	2009 - 2015
	B.S. (Computer Science)	
*	Command day Secondary School NAFRC-Oshodi, Lagos	1999 - 2005
	Science (SSCE/WAEC & NECO)	

Other Certifications

*	Google Ads & Video	Google
*	Mobile App Development (using Flutter)	Zuri Internship
*	Fullstack (Frontend-html, CSS, JS + Python & Django)	Zuri Internship
*	UX/UI Design - Graduate Accelerator Program	Stutern
*	UX/UI Design	SideHustle Internship
*	Web UI/UX Development Including (HTML, CSS & WordPress)	CodeLagos

Interests

New technologies, Entertainment & Arts, traveling, music.